silverchair.com 2019-09-05

# Privacy Policy - Silverchair

_Effective Date: May 16, 2018_

Silverchair values and prioritizes privacy and complies with industry standards to protect the security of user information. By continuing to use our website, and by submitting information to us through this website, you are consenting to the collection, use, and sharing of your information in accordance with this privacy policy. This policy pertains to the privacy practices for [www.silverchair.com](http://www.silverchair.com/) (the “Site”), owned and operated by Silverchair Information Systems. It is intended to inform our users of the data collected by the site and how it is used and stored.  Please read this Privacy Policy carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding your information and how we will treat it.  If you do not agree with any part of this Privacy Policy, please do not use our Site.

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time.  The “Effective Date” legend at the top of the page indicates when this Privacy Policy was last revised.  Any changes will become effective when we post the revised Privacy Policy on the Site.  Your continued use of the Site following such changes means that you accept the revised Privacy Policy.

### Information Collection, Use, and Sharing

In our ongoing effort to provide users with the most relevant information and to continually improve our site and communications, we collect information provided directly by our users, from cookies, and from server logs, as described below.

### Information We Collect

Users may provide personally identifiable information (“Personal Information”) to Silverchair when you communicate with us via the site’s Contact Us form or sign up for our e-mail newsletter.  The information we collect includes your name, telephone number, e-mail address and other information you choose to share with us.  You are not required to provide Personal Information to us, but if you choose not to share Personal Information, you may not be able to use or access certain features of the Site.

Silverchair’s server logs automatically collect and store some information when you visit and navigate through our Site. This information includes your IP address, visit time, browser type, and pages viewed. This information is aggregated and used to identify site traffic patterns and improve user experiences.

### Cookies

Though Silverchair does not use cookies, third-party tracking software installed on the site, such as Google Analytics, does.  A cookie is a piece of data stored on a site visitor’s hard drive to help identify user journeys and repeat visitors to our site. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information on our site. If desired, users may choose to manage the use of cookies directly on their browser settings.  Although users are not required to accept cookies, blocking or rejecting cookies may prevent access to some features available through the Site.

### The Purposes For Which We Use Your Information

You agree that we may use your Personal Information as follows:

  * To establish and manage business relations with you;
  * To respond to your queries, and provide you with services or information that you request from us;
  * For customer service, security, or to detect fraud or illegal activities;
  * To prevent or investigate activity we think may be potentially illegal, unlawful, or harmful;
  * For archival and backup purposes in connection with the operation of the Site;
  * To better understand how you use and access the Site, for purposes of trying to improve the Site, diagnose problems, and administer our Site; and
  * To enforce our Site [Terms of Use](https://www.silverchair.com/terms-of-use/) or other applicable policies.

### How We Share Information

Any information we gather, whether voluntarily provided by you or automatically collected, may be used for our internal business purposes and disclosed to third parties as stated below.  We treat the Personal Information you submit to us as confidential.  We may share Personal Information with other trusted companies or people to perform functions for which we engage them, such as our newsletter e-mail vendor, provided that those third parties use your Personal Information only to perform such services or to comply with legal requirements.  also share certain non-identifying information with the vendors who help us administer the Site and analyze Site usage.

Notwithstanding any other statements or representations in this Privacy Policy or elsewhere on our Site, we reserve the right to disclose any information in our possession if we are required to do so by law or we believe, in good faith, that such a disclosure is necessary to comply with the law, court order or other government or law enforcement agency, defend our rights or property, prevent financial loss or physical harm, or to respond to an emergency situation or protect the rights, property or safety of others.

We may transfer your Personal Information to Silverchair affiliates within or outside the United States whose privacy policies meet or exceed our standards.  Silverchair also reserves the right to transfer Personal Information to a purchaser or successor entity in the event of a sale or other corporate transaction involving some or all of our business.

### How to Access or Update Your Information

You may request to view, edit, and delete your Personal Information that we process about you (including requesting confirmation whether we process Personal Information about you) by contacting us at the e-mail address provided below.  We will respond to your request within a reasonable time.  In some circumstances, if warranted, we may request confirmation of your identity and may charge a reasonable fee for access to such information.  In addition, users may adjust their communication settings or opt out of our newsletters by following the “Unsubscribe” link in those e-mails.

### Information Storage

Personal Information that we process for any purpose will not be retained for longer than is necessary for that purpose.  The retention of your Personal Information will be determined based on the nature of the query and any subsequent communications with us, but we will not retain any Personal Information you submit to us for longer than ninety days after our last communication with you, and you may request that we edit or delete your Personal Information at any time.  Notwithstanding the other provisions of this section, we may retain your Personal Information where we believe such retention is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

### Children Under the Age of 13

Our Site is not intended for or targeted to children under the age of 13.  Silverchair will never knowingly solicit or collect Personal Information from a child under the age of 13 through the Site without verifiable parental consent.  If we discover that a child under the age of 13 has submitted Personal Information without verifiable parental consent, we will delete that information.

### External Links

This Site includes links to external sites, each of which is governed by that site’s own privacy policies. Silverchair is not responsible for the content or privacy practices, including, without limitation, information collection, retention, or sharing practices, of any linked sites or any other external sites.  You should familiarize yourself with the privacy practices of each website that you visit, as your visit to that website will be governed by that website’s applicable privacy policy.

### Social Media Links

To facilitate the sharing of site content, some pages contain social media links. These plug-ins may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Please be sure to familiarize yourself with the privacy practices of each social media platform that you visit, as your visit to that platform will be governed by the platform’s applicable privacy policy.

### Additional Provisions Applicable to California Residents

If you are a California resident under 18 years of age and have an account with us or have linked to us through social media, you can request that we remove content or information that you have posted to our Site or other online services under our control.  Note that fulfillment of the request may not ensure complete or comprehensive removal (e.g., if the content or information has been reposted by another member).  To request removal of content or information, please e-mail us using the contact information below.

### Security

We (like all websites) cannot warrant or guarantee 100% security of any information you transmit to us through the Site.  However, Silverchair implements physical, technical, and administrative safeguards to protect your information both online and offline. Information we collect online is encrypted and transmitted to us in a secure way (you may verify this by looking for a lock icon and “https” in the address bar). We also protect your information offline by restricting employee access to the data we collect and by storing that data on secure servers.

### Managing “Do Not Track” Signals

Some browsers have a Do Not Track (“DNT”) feature that lets you tell websites that you do not want your online activities tracked.  When you choose to turn on the DNT setting in your browser, your browser sends a special signal to websites, ad networks, plug-in providers, and other web services you encounter while browsing to stop tracking your activity via cookies or other tracking technologies.  Our Site currently does not respond to DNT signals. Response to DNT signals by third-parties who provide tracking software used on the Site is based on those companies’ settings.

### Complaints, Questions, or Concerns

If you have questions about this privacy policy, please [contact us](https://www.silverchair.com/contact/).

Any data subject may approach our Chief Data Protection Officer at any time to raise concerns, ask questions, request information or make complaints relating to data protection or data security issues.  You can contact our Chief Data Protection Officer at [dataprivacy@silverchair.com](mailto:dataprivacy@silverchair.com).

In addition, if you are a resident of the European Union and consider that our processing of your Personal Information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection, for example, in the EU member state of your habitual residence.
